Chris Ross

chrislross.com chrislross@outlook.com 306-716-9046

Personal Profile

I am a senior software developer with experience in quantitative finance and data protection. I have been designing, implementing, and testing software systems professionally for the last 5 years. However, I have been writing software for much longer than that. I have work experience in C/C++ and C#, but I am proficient in many other languages as well.

Education

University of Saskatchewan

2011-2015

B.Sc. Honours Computer Science

Recognition

High Honours

University of Saskatchewan, 2015 For having a graduating average over 80%

Guaranteed Entrance Scholarship

University of Saskatchewan, 2011 For having an admission average over 85%

Experience

TD

2018 - Present

Senior Software Developer

Treasury Department

I work on a quantitative modelling platform for the treasury department. The software is responsible for valuation, risk analysis, and hedging of the bank's assets and liabilities. I work mainly in C# and C++ in a Windows development environment. I have gained a strong understanding of financial and accounting principles from this role.

Dell EMC

2015 - 2017

Software Developer II

Data Protection Division

Associate Software Developer

Data Protection Division

I developed data-center backup & recovery software using mainly C, C++, and C#. Development was done in both Linux and Windows development environments. I worked closely with relational databases like Microsoft SQL Server, etc. I gained experience working within a highly distributed international team. I was responsible for the planning, design, and implementation of new features. I also occasionally resolved high priority customer escalations.

Projects

0S432

A simple operating system for the Raspberry Pi written in ARM assembly and C.

Pleasantville

An open world graphics sandbox programmed in C++ using OpenGL.

christross.com

My website. Hosted on GitHub